Finding Aid for Frank F. Pray Papers 1908-1969
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Frank F. Pray Papers 1908-1969 1910-1915
Pray, Frank F.
Jackson, Michigan physician; medical records, files pertaining to farm business, and personal miscellaneous.
9425 Aa 2
2.7 linear feet in 4 boxes
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
This collection is part of a series of donations made by the Pray family (donor no. 4444 ).
The collection is open for research.
Frank Freeman Pray was born the third child of Dr. George W. and Adele Pray (maiden name Pope). Before enrolling at the University of Michigan in 1910, he oversaw the family's farm on Woodard Lake in Ionia, Michigan. Pray received his MD from Michigan's Homeopathic Medical School in 1915 and began practicing in Parma in Jackson County. Around 1920 he moved his practice to his family's new home in Jackson and practiced in that city for approximately 45 years, continuing to rent out and oversee the family farmstead remotely. Pray retired from medicine and returned to the Ionia farm in 1967. He died in 1969.
The Frank F. Pray collection is comprised of three series: Medical, Farm Business, and Personal. The papers include documentation of his medical education and aspects of his medical practices, a small amount of material on the Pray family farm, and correspondence relating to Pray family history.
Subjects:
Physicians--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Pray, Frank F.; University of Michigan--Examinations.; University of Michigan--Students--Outlines, syllabi, etc.; University of Michigan. Homoeopathic Medical School.; Physicians--Michigan--Jackson.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Pray, Frank F.; Pray, George R. (George Raymond), 1878-1967.
Genre/Form:
Greeting cards.; Business cards.; Photographs.
- Medical
  The Medical series (2.2 linear feet) consists of materials relating to Pray's medical training and career. The series is comprised primarily of notebooks, blue books, and examinations, covering a wide variety of fields, from his education at the University of Michigan medical school from 1910 to 1915. Also included in this series are professional correspondence, medical books, and several office appointment books from late in his professional career (1943-1966).
  - Medical School Notes and Examinations
    - Infectious Diseases notes 1911-1915 (Box 1)
    - Obstetrics blue books 1913-1914, 5 volumes (Box 1)
    - Physiology blue books 1911, 6 volumes (Box 1)
    - Obstetrics notes (Box 1)
    - Chemistry blue books 1910-1911, 7 volumes (Box 1)
    - Thesis-History of Chemistry 1911 (Box 1)
    - Ophthalmology and Otolaryngology notes (Box 1)
    - Gynecology notes (Box 1)
    - Normal Anatomy-notes and drawings 1912 (Box 1)
    - Histology notes and drawings 1911-1912 (Box 1)
    - Pathology Laboratory blue books, 41 volumes (Box 1)
    - Chemistry notes (Box 1)
    - Organic Chemistry notes (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Rhetoric (notes) and legal lectures outlines (Box 1)
    - Gynecology blue books 1915, 2 volumes (Box 1)
    - Ophthalmology (Box 1)
    - Otolaryngology (Box 1)
    - Refraction (Box 1)
    - Surgery blue books 1912-1914, 8 volumes (Box 1)
    - Materia Medica notes 1912-1914 (Box 1)
    - Physiological Chemistry lecture and lab notes (Box 1)
    - Physiology notes, drawings, and lectures (Box 1)
    - Physical Diagnosis and Medical Clinic (Box 1)
    - Extrinsic Causes of Disease notes (Box 1)
    - Bacteriology notes (Box 1)
    - Hematology and Hygiene notes (Box 1)
    - Bacteriology Lab notes and drawings 1912-1913 (Box 1)
    - Surgery notes and drawings 1914 (Box 1)
    - Diseases-Mental and Nervous System 1914-1915 (Box 1)
    - Physiology lab drawings circa 1911 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous publications, etc
    - Sketches (Box 2)
    - Notebooks-miscellaneous fields (Box 2)
    - Office appointment books circa 1943-1966, 16 volumes (Box 2)
    - University of Michigan Unofficial Student's Directory, 1914 (Box 2)
    - Directory of Phi Alpha Gamma Fraternity 1894-1925 (Box 2)
    - A Laboratory Outline of General Chemistry by Alexander Smith (Box 2)
    - Thirty-seventh Annual Announcement of the Homoeopathic Medical College of the University of Michigan, 1911-1912 (Box 2)
    - Thirty-Eighth Annual Announcement of the Homoeopathic Medical College of the University of Michigan, 1912-1913 (Box 2)
    - Self-Cultivation in English by George Herbert Palmer (Box 2)
    - The Technic of the Chicago Lying-In Hospital and Dispensary (Box 2)
    - Notebook-drugs received 1948-1953 (Box 2)
    - Medical School Notes, Examinations 1914 (Box 3)
    - Federal Narcotics Record Book 1915 (Box 3)
    - Medical Pamphlets circa 1920-1960 (Box 3)
    - Medical Correspondence
      - 1915-1935 (Box 3)
      - 1945-1958 (Box 3)
    - Foote Hospital-Memos and Newsletter 1954-1965 (Box 3)
- Farm Business
  The Farm Business series (.1 linear feet) includes correspondence related to the farm Pray owned and let from c.1908 to 1913. Also included are documents, notes and correspondence from 1942 to 1943, primarily concerning the finances of Pray's farm.
  - 1908-1911 (Box 3)
  - 1910-1913 (Box 3)
  - 1942-1943 (Box 3)
  - Farm Drawings (Box 3)
- Personal
  The Personal series (.2 linear feet) includes primarily correspondence from friends and family, a substantial portion of which is from Pray's daughter Jeanne and his brother George R. Other interesting material relates to newspaper articles concerning the Pray legacy at the University of Michigan and Pray family reunions in the 1930s.
  - Photographs-Frank F. and George R. Pray (Box 3)
  - Correspondence
    - 1917-1969 (Box 3)
    - George R. Pray 1943-1954 (Box 3)
    - Regarding George W. Pray Student Material 1937, 1968 (Box 3)
    - Helen Reddaway, London 1942 (Box 3)
  - General
    - Receipts, correspondence-Ann Arbor businesses 1910-1916 (Box 3)
    - Lost Lake Woods Club-Lincoln, MI 1935-1945 (Box 3)
    - Pray family reunion (Box 3)
    - Organization memberships (Box 3)
    - Poster 1908 (Box 4)
    - Scrapbook/Album (Box 4)